Jann Barron

Senior Database Administrator - Senior Database Administrator/Data Engineer - CSG Systems International

Denver, CO - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Jann-Barron/6173eb9d2afe7be6

I have 19 years experience as a database administrator and 13 years experience in systems engineering and information technology. My background has been in various fields such as telecommunications engineering, broadband, aerospace, aviation, and customer care solutions. I enjoy meeting the challenge of working with a team to achieve the successful development of software applications and databases.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Database Administrator - Senior Database Administrator/Data Engineer

CSG Systems International - December 2000 to May 2017

Currently Lead DBA for development teams for Work Force Automation (WFX), Standalone Capacity Planning (SCX) and Direct Sales Express (DSX) databases using Oracle OLTP databases on Solaris and Linux.

- -Coordinate all database releases to development, QA and production plus writing customized databases patches using PL/SQL (updates, procedures, functions, triggers).
- Currently Lead DBA for eCare Express supporting clients such as Comcast, Echostar, Time Warner and Charter Communications using AIX and db2 LUW v9.7/10.5 OLTP development and QA databases.
- -Responsible for all Oracle upgrades, migrations, Critical Patch Updates and quarterly Patch Set Updates.
- Responsible for performance and tuning, troubleshooting, backup/recovery, buffer pools, indexing, and managing resource usage for both Oracle and db2.
- Responsible for migrating all Oracle instances and databases from 8i up through 11.2.0.4. Currently installing and configuring Oracle 12c for future upgrades.
- Responsible for all db2 upgrades including IBM software upgrades and migrations, Fix Packs, and third party vendor software upgrades.

Lead DBA

CSG Systems International - 2016 to 2017

to Linux project. Built numerous instances/clients on multiple Linux servers using ASM and grid. Migrated Solaris Oracle databases to Linux using Data Pump, implemented database replication using Golden Gate and am responsible for migrating all of development and QA. Currently helping the production DBA's set up Linux instances and Golden Gate for migrating all of production in 2016-17.

- Lead DBA for Cablevision/Fibertel (Argentinean/Brazilian cable company) using Oracle 11.2.0.4 on Linux. Built proof of concept databases, worked with digraphs and helped translate key elements into Spanish. My team was subsequently awarded a multi-million dollar contract and we have brought a production Spanish version of WFX online as of May 2016. We are currently working on a proof of concept for a similar company in Mexico.
- -Was a production DBA for ten years, participated in on-call rotation, and was responsible for numerous Oracle and db2 production databases.
- -Part of team that successfully ported all of WFX from Sybase to Oracle back in 2001.

Lead Database Administrator - Internet Systems Support Engineering

U.S. West Dex/QWEST - April 1994 to October 2000

- Responsible for Sybase ASE database administration and 24x7 support for 25 databases on fifteen Sun Solaris machines in an IPOP/EPOP which supported the US West DEX White and Yellow page web site.

- Supported daily, weekly, monthly and quarterly administration applications that refreshed data in all yellow and white page databases. Automated all processes for weekend runs.

Information systems experience prior to 1994 available upon request:
McDonnell Douglas (software developer)
Jeppeson Sanderson (software developer)
MicroAnalysis and Design (software testing/QA)
CACI (software developer)

EDUCATION

Graduate Studies Program

University Colorado Denver - Denver, CO 2014

certificate in Graduate Studies Program

University Colorado Denver - Denver, CO 2013

PhD

Pennsylvania State University - Middletown, PA 1987

certificate in Geography

University of Colorado Boulder - Boulder, CO 1987

Master of Arts in Geography/Cartography

SUNY Albany - Albany, NY 1983

Bachelor of Arts in Pittsburgh

University of Pittsburgh - Johnstown, PA 1981